Muzammil Shabbir

muzammilsaeed49@gmail.com Lahore, Pakistan +923319744361

Personal Statement

Energetic software engineer with 1+ year of experience developing mobile and web applications for high-volume businesses. Contributed in a product that the company is planning to sell as a SaaS product. An enthusiastic team player and creative thinker having expertise in full stack development

Experience

Software Engineer - Mobile Application Developer

Jugnu Tech(B2B) Lahore, Pakistan (Aug 2021 - Present)

- Contributing in developing Warehouse Management System (WMS) for iOS and Android devices using React Native.
- Revamped the user interface of WMS.
- Implemented Typescript, Redux Toolkit in WMS.
- Replaced the class component with the functional component.
- Wrote test cases using jest.

Software Engineer – Internship

NodeSol Corp, Lahore, Pakistan (April 2021 - July 2021)

- Contributed in developing full stack store management system for mobile devices.
- Contributed in full stack web application like zameen.com.
- Integrated API's in various Projects.

Expertise	 Full Stack Web Application Development Hybrid Mobile Apps Development Problem Solving
Programming Languages	Javascript/TypeScript
Frameworks and Technologies	 NodeJS (Express) React JS React Native Next JS Redux Toolkit Postman Tailwind CSS Jest
Databases	MongoDB, SQL, NoSQL, Firebase/Firestore

Education

• BS Software Engineering (Bachelor's Degree) 2017-2021 COMSATS Institute of Information Technology Lahore, Pakistan

• F.Sc – Engineering (High School)

DPS College Okara, Pakistan

2014-2016

• Matriculation (Secondary School)

2012-2014

DPS School Okara, Pakistan

Achievements

- Group Leader for Final Year Project which scored 3.7 out of 4.
- CIIT top 5% entry test scholarship.
- Stood 1st in Inter College Table Tennis Tournament.

Interests

Foodie | Sports | Travel | Movies